# TERRY ZHOU | Full Stack Software Developer

#### About me

I'm a full stack developer with a deep passion for clarity, creative solutions, and collaborative success. As a lifelong learner, I am constantly honing my skills to become a stronger coder and a more effective teammate. My experience as a realtor in a tough market has taught me how to achieve results under pressure, and I have strong organizational and interpersonal skills that make me an asset on any team!

#### **Skills**

Languages - Python, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3 | Libraries and Frameworks - Node.js, React, Express Database - PostgreSQL, Sequelize, MongoDB, Mongoose | Other - RESTful Routing, JSON, AJAX, MERN

### **Software Development Projects**

**MAY - JULY 2021** 

Game of Life - Capstone project running a fully-functional simulation of Conway's Game of Life.

- Five-day sprint challenge coded in Python and Pygame.
- Features full user interactivity, pause/reset functionality, music, and sound effects
- Includes three alternate variations of the Game of Life, with the ability to switch between variations in real time at the tap of a button.
- Contains a variety of built-in starter functions to generate popular Game of Life constructs such as Gosper Glider Guns, Beacons, Beehives, and Replicators.
- Github Repo

**Totemize -** First collaborative sprint: my team created a prototype for a full stack festival & events application that allows users to login, search for and add their friends, create and share events, and locate one another on a mockup festival map.

- Three-day sprint coding competition involving collaboration between coders and a UI/UX team.
- Full stack MERN app using JWT tokens and hashes for user security.
- Styled according to UI/UX specifications with a slick, efficient, mobile-first design philosophy.
- Back-end Repo | Front-end Repo | App on Netlify

**PokéMap -** Full stack application that uses Sequelize to store Pokemon data on the back-end, and renders a map of the Kanto region + Pokedex on the front end.

- Used Postman/Axios to make RESTful API fetch calls to pokeapi.co and serebii.net, handling all
  create, read, update, delete (CRUD) operations, and created routes for all JSONified data through
  Express.
- Used Sequelize and PostgreSQL to organize fetched information into databases, allowing users to
  explore the map, examine Pokemon found on different routes, add them to their party and view a
  wealth of detailed data.
- Implemented ejsLayouts, Grid, Bootstrap and vanilla CSS to style maps, tables, and other front-end resources.
- Github Repo | App on Heroku

**Cat Crawler -** One-week sprint where I created a dungeon crawler-style video game featuring a cat player character.

- Learned and utilized HTML5's built-in Canvas API along with CSS & JS to create an in-browser game.
- Engineered flexible and responsive code allowing enemies to track & pursue the player within a given radius.
- Fully styled with music, sound effects, HUD elements, and other details to enhance the user's gameplay experience.
- Github Repo | Playable Link

## **Professional Experience**

#### JP & Associates Realtors - Licensed Realtor | Austin, TX

MAY 2020 - Present

- Negotiated deals for buyers at 30-50% below asking price in a hot seller's market.
- Located homes and apartments for 6-10 renter clients per month.
- Created a personal referral network with an 80% returning client rate.

#### Property Manager | Austin, TX

MAR 2017 - NOV 2020

- Increased client profits by 10-20% by leasing properties at above average market value.
- Curated and promoted an AirBnB with an average of 1-2 clients per week.
- Managed 20-25 properties per month in the Greater Austin Area.

#### Education

#### General Assembly | Remote

MAY 2021 - Present

#### **Software Engineering Immersive**

- Attended an 80+ hours/weekly software development bootcamp focused on product development fundamentals, object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and team collaboration strategies.
- Developed a portfolio of individual projects and learned full stack technologies & frameworks, including HTML/CSS/JavaScript, SQL, MongoDB, Axios, and Node.
- Familiar with Git and version control, including both managing and contributing to team projects, as well as team management softwares such as Slack and Microsoft Teams.

# Southwestern University | Georgetown, TX Bachelor's Degree in Biology

SEPT. 2011 - MAY 2015

- Performed genetic knockout trials on various breast, ovarian, and endometrial cancer cell lines in order to test potential gene therapy treatments.
- Used CRISPR-Cas9 proteins coded with guide RNAs to modify cancer cell lines and monitor changes in cell membranes over the course of a year.
- Volunteered to care for in-patients at a local hospital undergoing surgery and chemotherapy.